Guide to the Collection of Barack Obama Ephemera from African Countries
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Collection of Barack Obama ephemera from African countries
2008-2010
MS 1990
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4
(6 boxes)
This collection consists of textiles, commemorative objects, and publications documenting African response to the election of Barack Obama as President of the United States in 2008.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator, 2013.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of textiles, commemorative objects, and publications documenting African response to the election of Barack Obama as President of the United States in 2008.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged according to format.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Presidents -- United States; Africa; Obama, Barack, 1961-
- Commemorative objects
  - Beaded magnet, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Made in South Africa.
  - Buttons, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
  - Decorative tassel, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - President Special Edition Lager beer bottle, 2008 (Box 2)
    From Nairobi, Kenya; bottle is empty.
- Printed material, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes flyer, pamphlet, bumper sticker, congratulatory note and a general description of material.
- Published material
  - Newspapers
    - Cameroon
      - The Post Weekender, #01001, 2008 November 7 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Kenya
      - The Standard, #28160-28162, 2008 November 5-7 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Taifa Leo, #165396-165397, 2008 November 5-6 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Nigeria
      - The Guardian, #10906-10907, 2008 November 5-6 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Daily Independent, volume 3, #1609, 2008 November 5 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - South Africa
      - Die Afrikaner, #1863, 2008 November 7-13 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Tanzania
      - Uhuru, #20087, 2008 November 6 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Uganda
      - Sunday Vision, volume 15, #46, 2008 November 16 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Sunday Magazine, 2008 November 16 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Who Am I? The Story of Barack Obama, by Phyllis Andrews, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Textiles with Obama's image and slogans
  - T-shirts, 2008 (Box 4)
    Three are from Kenya and one (grey) is from South Africa.
  - Fabric remnants, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Fabric remnant, 2009 (Box 6)
  - Baseball cap, 2008 (Box 6)